A Guide to the M. Caldwell Butler Papers 1945-2006
Lewis F. Powell, Jr. Archives, Washington and Lee University
- Bankruptcy Legislation 1972-1978, 18 cu. ft.
  - Ken Klee's Bankruptcy Files
    - Uniform Bankruptcy File
      - Witness List Committee on the Judiciary on H.R. 31 and H.R. 32 April 9, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Memorandum from Klee re: Stockbrokerage Bankruptcy April 7, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Witness List, Hearings and testimony re: H.R. 31 and H.R. 32 April 12, 1976
      - Memorandum from Klee re: Subcommittee Agenda (Carton 72)
      - Conference Report # 94-938 on Municipal Bankruptcy Law Revision March 22, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Memorandum from Klee re: Transition Hearings May 3, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Memorandum from Klee re: Railroad Reorganization April 14, 1976
      - Letter to Hon. Don Edwards from Rhonderick M. Hills April 16, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Report of the Securities and Exchange Commission on H.R. 31 and H.R. 32 (Carton 72)
      - Summary of Principal recommendations of the Securities and Exchange Commission on H.R. 31 and H.R. 32 April 19, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Supplement to report of the SEC on H.R. 31 and H.R. 32 (Carton 72)
      - Statement of Jack N. Bohm, re: H.R. 31 and H.R. 32; S. 235, S. 236 April 19, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Witness List, Committee on the Judiciary, H.R. 31 and H.R. 32 April 24, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Witness List, Committee on the Judiciary, H.R. 31 and H.R.32 April 27, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Title 45, Railroad, Sec. 11140, 155, 11142 (Carton 72)
      - Memorandum to Butler from Klee re: Delmarva Labor Situation April 29, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Witness List/ Testimony, Committee on the Judiciary, H.R. 31 and H.R. 32 April 29, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Statement of Rep. Matthew J. Rinaldo April 30, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Witness List/ Testimony, Committee on the Judiciary, H.R. 31 and H.R. 32 May 3, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Letter to Hon. Don Edwards from Michael Ulmann May 3, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Department of Justice Detailed Comments on H.R. 32 April 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Department of Justice Overview Comments on H.R. 32 April 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Memorandum to Butler from Klee re: Railroad Reorganizations May 4, 1976 (Carton 72)
        Enclosed copy of RRRA and RRRRA
      - Letter to Philip E. Ruppe from Butler re: Thank you for letter of May 4, 1976 May 12, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Statement of William G. Mahoney on H.R. 31 and H.R. 32 May 13, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Memorandum to members of the Subcommittee on Civil and Constitutional Rights from Cong. Don Edwards, Chairman May 18, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - "Pro Per Report" by John Roberto, University of California, on the subject of Consumer Bankruptcies/ Notebook, H.R. 10624 Conference Briefing Book January 21, 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Tables of Bankruptcy Statistics with reference to Bankruptcy Cases commenced and terminated in the U.S. District Courts during the period July 1, 1976 - June 30, 1977 (Carton 72)
      - New York State Bar Association Tax Section / Letter from Ginsburg January 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Linn K. Twinem's information 1976 (Carton 72)
      - Statement of William T. Bagley on H.R. 31 and H.R. 32 July 1976 (Carton 72)
    - Municipal Bankruptcy File (Mun) (Carton 73)
      - Preliminary Draft of Proposed Bankruptcy Rules and Official Forms Under Chapter IX of the Bankruptcy Act, by the Committee on Rules of Practice and procedure of the Judicial Conference of the United States. July, 1974 (Carton 73)
      - H.R. 10792 October 9, 1973 (Carton 73)
      - Memo from Don Edwards, Chairman of Subcommittee on Civil Rights and Constiutional Rights, and summary of major recommendations on H.R. 10792 January 15, 1974 (Carton 73)
      - "The Establishment of the Commission", 2 copies (Carton 73)
      - Amendment to H.R. 10264 offered by Mr. Butler (Carton 73)
      - Colloquy 1-8 (Carton 73)
      - Extension of Remarks re: H.R. 10624 by Don Edwards December 8, 1975 (Carton 73)
      - Amendments to H.R. 10624, as Reported, offered by Ms. Holtzman (Carton 73)
      - Memorandum from Klee October 1, October 30, November 4, 1975 (Carton 73)
      - H.R. 10454 October 30, 1975 (Carton 73)
      - H.R. 10457 October 30, 1975 (Carton 73)
      - White House draft of President's proposal to amend the Bankruptcy Act to add a new chapter concerning major municipalities October 30, 1975 (Carton 73)
      - Department of Justice Analysis of Mun-13 (Carton 73)
      - Amendment in the nature of a substitute offered to H.R. 10454 November 4, 1975 (Carton 73)
      - Collection of Background Information (Carton 73)
      - H.R. 10264: A Summary (Carton 73)
      - "Bankruptcy Reform: A New IX?" The Banking Law JournalAugust 1975 (Carton 73)
      - Release by Rep. Badillo, "Rep Badillo Introduces Legislation to Simplify Procedures for Filing Municipal Bankruptcy" September 30 (Carton 73)
      - "If New York Goes Bankrupt --" U.S. News and World ReportSeptember 15, 1975 (Carton 73)
      - Memorandum from Don Edwards October 2, 1975 (Carton 73)
      - Testimony of John R. Butler October 3, 1975 (Carton 73)
      - Statement of George Hempel, Professor of Finance, Washington University October 6, 1975 (Carton 73)
      - Statement by C.W.F. Spencer, Jr., atty October 6, 1975 (Carton 73)
      - Statement of Antonin Scalia, Asst. Atty. General, Office of Legal Counsel October 6, 1975 (Carton 73)
      - Statement of Benjamin Weintraub of the New York Bar (Carton 73)
      - H.R. ___ to revise Chpater IX of the Bankruptcy Act (Carton 73)
      - Senate Report of Judiciary Committee Hearings on S. 2597 October 31, 1975 (Carton 73)
      - Senate Report of Judiciary Committee Hearings on S. 2597 November 4, 1975 (Carton 73)
    - Bankruptcy Act Subject Files (Ken Klee's Files)
      - File Order and Bibliographies (Carton 74)
      - General Information (Carton 74)
      - General Correspondence 1973-1974 June-December 1975 January-April 1976 August-December 1976 January-March 1977 May-July 1977 (Carton 74)
      - Summary of Full Committee Meetings July 1977 (Carton 74)
      - Administartion v. Judicial Functions (Carton 74)
      - Bankruptcy Act-Current Redrafts (Carton 74)
      - Bankruptcy Court/Trustee/Judicial Conference (Carton 74)
      - Commodities (Carton 74)
      - Consumer Bankruptcy (Carton 74)
      - Costs/Benefits (Carton 74)
      - Education Loans (Carton 74)
      - Exemptions (Carton 74)
      - Fenwick & Consumers (Carton 74)
      - Department of Justice Materials-Bankruptcy (Carton 74)
      - International Bankruptcy (Carton 74)
      - Miscellaneous Lobbying Propaganda (Carton 74)
      - NBC/MCBJ Compromise (Carton 74)
      - Railroad Reorganization (Carton 74)
      - SIPA 1970/SIPA 1975/Stockbroker Bankruptcy (Carton 74)
      - Solicitations & Proxies & SEC Security Issues (Carton 74)
      - Stay of State Police Power (Carton 74)
      - Statements for the record (Carton 74)
      - Taxes-IRC (Carton 75)
      - Transportation (Carton 75)
      - Wage Earner Plans (Carton 75)
      - Bankruptcy Voting Breakdown/Article III Judges (Carton 75)
      - Danielson/Railsback Amendment Materials (Carton 75)
      - Bankruptcy Student Loans/Colleague Letters/Community Reaction (Carton 75)
      - Bankruptcy Cost Estimates /Powers-Article III Judges (Carton 75)
      - Bankruptcy/Community Support/Colleague Letters (Carton 75)
      - Bankruptcy/Extra Materials (Carton 75)
- Legal Services Corporation Act, 1 cu. ft. (Carton 50)
  Legal Services Corporation Act papers consist of one cu. ft. of materials concerning the authorization of funding for this entity for the fiscal years 1982-1984. Included here are: the authorization bill, itself; correspondence; "discussion papers"; press clippings; transcripts of testimony and hearing proceedings. (The one file of material about the re-authorization of the Department of Justice follows the Legal Services papers.)
  - Amendments 1980, 1981 (Carton 76)
  - Oversight Hearings February 26, 1981 (Carton 76)
  - Reauthorization 1981 (Carton 76)
  - Hearings (Carton 76)
  - Reauthorization March 25, 1981 (Carton 76)
  - Oversight Hearings March 31, 1981 (Carton 76)
  - Reauthorization April 7, 1981 (Carton 76)
  - Judiciary Full Committee Mark-Up May 13, 1981 (Carton 76)
  - Correspondence 1981-1982 (Carton 76)
  - Federal Regulations (Carton 76)
  - Newspaper Articles (Carton 76)
  - Justice Department Reauthorization, FY 1982 (Carton 76)
- Voting Rights Act Extension 1981, 2 cu. ft. (Carton 77-78)
  The Voting Rights Act Extension series comprises Butler's legislative papers as a member of the House Judiciary Committee during the consideration of the extension of this Act.
- National Bankruptcy Review Commission, 16 cu. ft.
  The National Bankruptcy Review Commission papers are from Butler's service as a member of that body from 1995-1997. These 16 cu. ft. of materials include: correspondence; meeting minutes; memoranda and documents distributed to commission members; and the report of the commission and drafts of that report.
  - Commission Meeting Minutes (Carton 79)
    - Official, Electronic, diskette, WordPerfect 6.1 (Carton 79)
    - Drafts July 1996-May 1997, Paper (Carton 79)
  - Master List of Committee Materials, Electronic, diskette, WordPerfect 6.1 (Carton 79)
  - Key to Arrangement of Commission Documents 1996-1997 June (Carton 79)
  - Numbered Documents, #1-#23 (Carton 79)
  - Numbered Documents #24-#42 (Carton 80)
  - Correspondence (Carton 81)
    - General 1994-1997 (Carton 81)
    - Subject (Carton 81)
  - Committee Mailings and Papers
    - Mailings 1995 (Carton 82)
    - Mailings 1996 January-April (Carton 83)
    - Mailings 1996 May-June (Carton 84)
    - Mailings 1996 July-August (Carton 85)
    - Mailings 1996 September - October (Carton 86)
    - Mailings 1997 (Carton 87)
  - Mailing Enclosures
    - Enclosures 1996 December - 1997 June (Carton 88)
    - Enclosures 1997 July - September (Carton 89)
  - Un-arranged Corresopndence and Papers 1996-1997 (Carton 90-91)
    Box 91 includes audio cassette of "discharge/reaffirmation hearing," 1997.
  - Papers re Consumer Bankruptcy 1997 (Carton 92)
  - Commission Report and Drafts of Report 1997 (Carton 93)
  - Published Materials re bankruptcy c. 1993-1997 (Carton 94)
- Artifacts 1976, 1998 (Carton 95)
  Bicentennial of American Revolution Flag; Bicentennial Medal, 1976; American College of Bankruptcy Commendation plaque, March 14, 1998.
- Oversize Materials 1972-1982, 1 oversize folder in map cases (Carton 3)
  Contents: 24"x36 inch photo of Butler, c. 1961; House Concurrent Resolution 672, July 1, 1976; Washington and Lee University Honorary Doctor of Laws Diploma, June 1, 1978; Birthday card from staff, June 2, 1973; National Small Business Association Certificate of Recognition, October 1978; certificate, Governor George Allen (Virgini) naming Butler to Governor's Advisory Council on Self-Determination and Federalism, November 14, 1994.